(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-31T14:04:49.248467",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
愛され ないことは私が
I knew best of all
一番 知っていたの
that I wasn't loved.
それでも あなたは
Even so, you...
この痛みに 意味を与えてくれたから
...gave meaning to this pain.
信じた人と 思え...
With the person I believed in...
愛されないことは私が
I knew best of all
一番知っていたの
what it meant to be unloved.
それでもあなたは この痛みに 意味を与えてくれたから
Even so, you gave meaning to this pain,
壊れてしまう恋だとしても 信じたいと思えたんだよ
making me want to believe in this fragile love.
あなたなら私の全て 分かってくれる気がした
I felt like you would understand everything about me.
あなたを愛しすぎてしまう前に あなたを全て知る前に
Before I end up loving you too much, before I know everything about you,
空に願う どうか未来があるように
I pray to the sky, hoping there is a future,
回そう 一人泣いてるの
as I spin and cry alone.
小さな私の手に重たかったあなたの大きな手
Your large hands that rested on my small hands,
失いと願うほど苦しくなっていたの
had become so painful to fear losing.
首についた真っ赤な愛が消える前にあなたに会いたくて
Before the bright red love on my neck fades, I wanted to see you.
目を閉じると 巻き戻される 最後のあたたかい夜
When I close my eyes, the final warm night is rewound.
優しいその目と優しいその言葉 全て嘘じゃない言い聞かせて
Your gentle eyes and gentle words... I tell myself they weren't all lies.
これで最後の恋だと思うから だから繋ぎとめていたかったのに
Thinking this is my final love, that's why I wanted to hold on tight.
もう全て分かっているから もう私に近づかないでよ
Since I already understand everything, don't come close to me anymore.
果てしないこの苦しみまでをも 愛せるほど強い人はいないから
Because no one is strong enough to love even this endless suffering.
あなたを愛しているからずっと あなたが私を忘れるまで 星に願う どうか行かないで ずっと思い側にいて欲しい
Because I love you, always... until you forget me, I pray to the stars: please don't go, I want you by my side forever.
あなたを愛しすぎてしまう前に あなたを全て知る前に
Before I end up loving you too much, before I know everything about you,
空に願う どうか未来があるように 回そう 一人泣いてるの
I pray to the sky, hoping there is a future, as I spin and cry alone.
もう全て分かっているから もう私に近づかないでよ
Since I already understand everything, don't come close to me anymore.
果てしないこの苦しみまでをも 愛せるほど強い人はいないから
Because no one is strong enough to love even this endless suffering.
あなたを愛しているからずっと あなたが私を忘れるまで 星に願う どうか行かないで ずっと思い側にいて欲しい
Because I love you, always... until you forget me, I pray to the stars: please don't go, I want you by my side forever.
あなたを愛しすぎてしまう前に あなたを全て知る前に 空に願う どうか未来があるように 今もそう、一人泣いてるの
Before I end up loving you too much, before I know everything about you, I pray to the sky, hoping there is a future—still, even now, I'm crying alone.
今もそう、一人泣いてるの
Still, even now, I'm crying alone.
Ini kisahnya anak manusia
This is the story of a human child,
Kau bisa memanggilnya dengan nama iofi
you can call her by the name Iofi.
Sebuah konsonan yang menyulitkan Membuat lidahnya bosan tak bisa ucapkan
A difficult consonant that makes her tongue tired, unable to pronounce it.
Dia coba pahami setiap manusia Punya hebat punya cacat
She tries to understand every human, who has greatness and flaws.
Dia coba nikmati hidup ini cuma sekali
She tries to enjoy this life just once
Dia hanya punya modal cinta
She only has love as her capital
Yang dia embuskan dalam setiap lagunya
Which she exhales into every song of hers
Tak inginkan semua tuk suka
Not wanting everyone to like it
Dia hanya ingin tuliskan lagu
She just wants to write a song
Tentang semua yang ada dalam hatinya
About everything that is in her heart
Bila tak suka tentu saja tak mengapa
If you don't like it, of course that's fine
Sejak kecil dia punya mimpi jadi musisi atau apapun di bidang seni
Since childhood she had a dream to be a musician or anything in art
Tumbuh dewasa bulatlah sudah
Growing up, it became settled
Keputusannya tuk dapatkan mimpinya
Her decision to get her dream
Dia coba pahami setiap manusia
She tries to understand every human
Punya hebat punya cacat
Having greatness, having flaws
Dia coba nikmati hidup ini cuma sekali
She tries to enjoy this life just once
Dia hanya punya modal cinta
She only has love as her capital
Yang dia embuskan dalam setiap lagunya
Which she exhales into every song of hers
Tak inginkan semua tuk suka
Not wanting everyone to like it
Dia hanya ingin tuliskan lagu
She just wants to write a song
Tentang semua yang ada dalam hatinya
About everything that is in her heart
Bila tak suka tentu saja tak mengapa
If you don't like it, of course that's fine
Dia hanya punya modal cinta
She only has love as her capital
Yang dia embuskan dalam setiap lagunya
Which she exhales into every song of hers
Tak inginkan semua tuk suka
Not wanting everyone to like it
Dia hanya ingin tuliskan lagu
She just wants to write a song
Tentang semua yang ada dalam hatinya
About everything that is in her heart
Bila tak suka tentu saja tak mengapa
If you don't like it, of course that's fine
Dia hanya punya modal cinta
She only has love as her capital
Yang dia embuskan dalam setiap lagunya
Which she exhales into every song of hers
Tak inginkan semua tuk suka
Not wanting everyone to like it
Dia hanya ingin tuliskan lagu
She just wants to write a song
Tentang semua yang ada dalam hatinya
About everything that is in her heart
Bila tak suka tentu saja tak mengapa
If you don't like it, of course that's fine
Yoforia, obisa, halo!
Yoforia, obisa, hello!
Aku Iofi dari Iofi ID Hololive Indonesia first generation, halo, selamat datang di birthday live!
I'm Iofi from Hololive Indonesia first generation, hello, welcome to my birthday live!
And by the way, the hashtag is #IofiLucidDream, you can just tweet all of you can, okay?
And by the way, krisis tahu, tahu enggak, sebentar lagu itu r-nya enggak ada ya.
And by the way, you probably realized, right? That earlier song didn't have the letter 'r', you know.
Hai! There is no r whatsoever!
Right! There is no 'r' whatsoever!
Jadi kalian, coba, kalian sama enggak, sadar enggak, kalau aku kalian bisa nyanyi lagu ini karena enggak ada r-nya.
So you guys, try, did you guys notice, did you realize, that I, you guys could sing this song because there's no 'r'.
Tapi bagi yang enggak apa ya, bagi yang enggak nyadar nanti akan keluar versi cover song-nya, sono cover-nya juga ada, jadi nanti ditonton ya.
But for those who didn't, you know, didn't realize, later a cover song version will be released, that cover's place is also there, so please watch it later, okay?
Hai, double cover song!
Yes, double cover song!
And by the way, by the way, this guitar—
Jadi itu, ya, ini juga ada model ini, dan ini warna gitarnya juga ada, jadi loh, lihat deh. Hai!
So yeah, this also has this model, and this guitar color is also there, so look at that. Right!
And if you remember, I kind of like upload this guitar picture somewhere.
And if you remember, I kind of like uploaded this guitar picture somewhere.
Yes, tapi biasanya aku main gitar cuma di membership. Iya, jadi ini pertama kalinya aku main gitar selain di membership.
Yes, but usually I play guitar only on membership. Yeah, so this is my first time playing guitar other than on membership.
Ah, you should play guitar like around membership...
お待たせ
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
あの、メインギターの皆はもう知ってると思いますけど、
Um, I think most of you who play main guitar already know, but
あの、普通はギターはあのメインギターでしか引いてないんだけど、これがね、
normally the guitar is only played on the main guitar, but this
メインギターじゃなくて配信で初めてです。
is the first time on a stream!
いや、ちょっと、怖いんだけど、もう、まあまあまあ、どうでしたか？
Man, I'm a bit scared, but well, how was it?
どう？どう？可愛い？可愛い？いっぱいスクショ撮った？スクショ撮った？
How is it? Cute? Cute? Did you take lots of screenshots?
I hope you enjoy it!
And by the way, we still have a lot of more going on. So after this, there's going to be a lot and a lot of guests. So please wait for it.
And by the way, we still have a lot more guests coming up, so please wait for it.
この後もゲストがもりたくさんなので、楽しみにしていてくださいね。
There are still plenty of guests after this, so please look forward to it!
Don't forget to take a lot of screenshot.
Don't forget to take lots of screenshots!
可愛い！
Cute!
ろぎ、ろぎ、るちゅ、るちゅ、るちゅ、るちゅ
Rogi, rogi, luchu, luchu...
まあね、時間があればこれもね、またギター弾きたいなと思っております。はい！
Well, if I have time, I'd love to play the guitar again. Yes!
あ、オッケー？準備オッケー？オッケーオッケーオッケー。
Ah, okay? Ready? Okay, okay, okay.
オッケー？しっ！
Okay? Shh!
ではゲストパートにまた会おうね！Thank you! 次はシンガーシンゲストパート！
Well then, see you again in the guest part! Thank you!
どこから話せばいいんだろう
Where should I begin to speak?
待ちくたびれても
Even if I'm tired of waiting,
終わりだなんて言わせないから
I won't let you say it's the end.
書き殴った無意識の衝動を連れて
Taking along the unconscious impulses I scribbled down,
何もかも壊したら不可能を始めればいいんだ
If I break everything, then I can just begin the impossible.
There’s a reason that we came across in this world
There’s a reason that we caught the magnetic wave
傷つけ合う世界はどこへ
Where is the world where we hurt each other?
There’s a reason that we come and got the magnetic wave
傷付け続け合う 世界はどこへ
Where is the world where we keep hurting each other?
そう、愛のためだけにできるのは
So, the only thing I can do for love
君がそこにいるから 君だけを呼び続けるから
Is because you are there, keeping calling out only for you.
愛のために歌うのは
Singing for the sake of love,
そして共に生き抜くこと ずっと、君と
And surviving together, always, with you.
青色した空と波ひとつない鏡のような海を見てた
I was watching the blue sky and a sea like a mirror without a single wave.
どんな場所にたって どんな形になって どんな時代にだって見つけ出すよ
Wherever we are, whatever form we take, I will find you in any era.
さだめにさからって
Going against fate.
There’s a reason that we came across in this world
There’s a reason that we caught the magnetic wave
引き寄せ合う二人はどこへ
Where are the two people drawn together heading?
そう、愛のために進むのは 君がそこにいるから
So, the reason I move forward for love is because you are there.
僕だけが君を守るから
Because I alone will protect you.
愛のために願うのは そして誰も傷つけずに
Wishing for the sake of love, and without hurting anyone,
ずっと、隣で
Always, by your side.
僕らは越えてゆく すべての憎しみを
We will overcome all the hatred.
ニセモノの正義など捨ててしまえ
Throw away fake justice and the like.
そう、愛のために嘆るのは 君がそこにいるから
So, the reason I cry for love is because you are there.
We'll always be together
愛のために もう一度 今
For love, once more, now
枯れそうな夢 水を与えよう
Let's give water to our fading dreams
信じられるもの 一つだけ
As long as I have one thing to believe in
あればそれだけで大丈夫
That's all I need to be okay
流した涙 あきらめた事
The tears I shed, the things I gave up on
全部右ポケットに入れて
Put them all in my right pocket
隠していたのに 君はいつでも
And hid them, but you were always
気付いていたんだね
Noticing them, weren't you?
瞳閉じれば あの夕焼け空
When I close my eyes, that sunset sky
温もりは消えないよ
That warmth will never fade away
どんな時だって 君の笑顔
No matter what, your smile
この心ずっと照らしてくれるから
Will always illuminate my heart
愛のために 歩いてゆこう
For love, let's keep walking on
心に咲いた花を守ろう
Let's protect the flower blooming in our hearts
イオフィお誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday, Iofi!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
いやー、今年も来てくれてありがとう！
Man, thanks for coming again this year!
えー、どうもこんにちは、ときのそらです。
Um, hello everyone, I'm Tokino Sora.
よろしくお願いします。
Nice to meet you.
いやー、なんか、ね、バラード歌っちゃったね。
Man, we really sang a ballad, huh?
ねー。
Yeah.
より私すごい気になってるんだけど、なん、何個の…
More importantly, I'm really curious, how...
え、だって、あの…宇宙寒いからこれ暖かいよ。
Well, since space is cold, this keeps us warm.
え、宇宙にね、焚き火なんてできるんだね。
Wait, you can have a campfire in space?
できるよ、一応。だって酸素があるってことだ。
You can, sort of. That means there's oxygen.
酸素ないから、ないんだったらもう耐えないじゃん。
If there wasn't oxygen, we wouldn't last, right?
そう、暖かいよ、これ。
Yeah, it's warm.
そらちゃん、なんか、何何何？
Sora-chan, what's going on?
MCでこんなにまったり焚き火の前でこう、やる事ないよ。ちょっと変な感じがする。
Doing an MC this relaxed in front of a campfire feels weird.
普通にさ、ポーズした後にこう、「あ、やっと歌えたね」っていう感じじゃん？ねえじゃない？
Normally, right after a pose, it's like, "We finally sang it!" Right?
でもやっぱり今年のテーマもっとゆったりとか、落ち着く雰囲気欲しいから、そのダンスと、あの歌の後によりそう、マイクをね、ちょっと落としてここに座ってっていう、ね。
This year's theme is more relaxed and calm, so sitting down here.
でもいいね、まったりできるから、ちょっとのんびりしてお喋りできる感じ、いいと思う。
It's nice to chill out and chat leisurely.
えへへ、やったやった。
Hehe, yay!
今年誕生日2回ぐらいやったんだよね、毎年。
I had about two birthdays this year, every year.
今年も、去年も、おととしもってこと？そうそうそうそう。
This year, last year, and the year before? Yes, exactly.
今年で、来年も来る？え、もちろんもちろん、呼んでもらえればいつでも行くよ。あ、やった！
Will you come next year? Of course! If you invite me, I'll go anytime. Yay!
じゃあ、決定です。やった！やったー！
Then it's decided. Yay! Hooray!
この去年と今年も結構ハンドマイクで、あの、やってるからさ、
We've been using hand mics for both last year and this year.
なんか結構聞かせるみたいな感じの曲が多かったなっておもって。
There were a lot of songs where you really have to listen closely.
じゃあ来年はバリバリ踊ります、そしたら。踊る！踊り、やっぱりね、その好き、踊る。大好き！
So next year we'll dance all out! Dancing, I really love it.
好き好き好き。ね、いいよね。
Love, love, love it. Yeah, it's great.
今年のさ、テーマさっきも聞いて、バラードだって聞いて、
When I heard it was a ballad,
いやなんかバラードのさ、全体のさ、ライブするのってすごい難しいなって私は思っちゃうの。
I felt like doing a whole live concert with ballads is really difficult.
私はいつもダンスとかで見せるみたいなのをやるから、バラードで挑戦するのってすごいなって思ってて。
We usually show off our dance, so taking on ballads is amazing.
でもなんか自分にとってはあのバラードが一番声に似合うから、
For me, ballads suit my voice the best.
ね、そう、なんかもっと見せたいなと思ってて。
So I thought I wanted to show that off more.
うー、綺麗。宇宙、宇宙に来ました。
Woo, gorgeous. We've come to space.
だから、今年はちゃんと宇宙に行きたいですって。
So this year, we wanted to properly go to space, I said.
わあ、すごい！宇宙来ました、二人で。
Wow, amazing! We came to space, the two of us.
すごい、綺麗、本当に！お、なんかね、ちゃんと似合うじゃない？本当？
It's so pretty, really! It really suits us, doesn't it?
みんなもいっぱいスクリーンショット撮った？
Did you guys take lots of screenshots too?
撮った！撮った！
We did! We did!
似合うでしょ？ほら、めっちゃ可愛い！パンツァパンツァして！
Doesn't it suit me? Look, super cute! Do the panza panza!
お！
Oh!
可愛い〜！
So cute~!
お！もっと見て？
Oh! Look closer?
えっ、これ私の記念日じゃないんだ！
Wait, this isn't even my anniversary!
あ、そうか！
Ah, that's right!
やった！やった！やった！
Yay! Yay! Yay!
え、大丈夫だよ。はい！いっぱい撮りました、二人で。
Hey, it's okay. Yes! We took so many, the two of us.
うぇーい！うぇーい！
Yay! Yay!
はい、ということで今回はまだまだ言うので皆さん楽しみにしてください！
Yes, so there's still more to come, so everyone please look forward to it!
ねぇ、本当におめでとうだよー！
Hey, huge congratulations!
では来年また歌って踊ろうね、おめでとうー！
Well then, let's sing and dance again next year, congratulations!
はい、でみなさんありがとうございましたー！
Yes, and thank you everyone so much!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much!
またね！またね！
See you! See you!
何度も問いかけた 自問自答繰り返した先に 答えがあるのなら
I asked over and over, after repeating soul-searching questions, if there's an answer
このまま探してみようか
should I keep searching like this?
あなたの未来図に 私は少しでもいれたかな
I wonder if I could be even a little bit in your future map.
あなたのいない世界は 想像さえつかなかった
A world without you was something I couldn't even imagine.
もしもあなたが、あの子を選んだ瞬間に私が頭の中 駆け巡っていたのなら悔しいな
If at the moment you chose that girl, I was running through your head, how frustrating would that be.
こんなにもあなたのこと 好きになってしまう前に
Before I grew to love you this much,
せめてさよならの言葉告げて欲しかったなんて 勝手でワガママだよね
I wish you had at least said goodbye—how selfish and willful of me.
誰より想ってるのに あなたを世界で1番笑顔に
Even though I care more than anyone, making you the happiest smile in the world
変えられる人はきっと 私じゃないから
the person who can change that definitely isn't me, so
どうか幸せになって
please be happy.
どんなに願っても変わりはしないこの現実が ただただ目の前の光全て奪い去っていった
No matter how much I wish, this reality won't change, simply taking away all the light before my eyes.
生まれ変わっても もう一度あなたに恋するかな
Even if I'm reborn, would I fall in love with you all over again?
そんな妄想なんて考えることすらバカみたい
Such delusions—even thinking about them is stupid.
こんなにもあなたのこと 好きになってしまう前にわざとさ優しい言葉で勘違いさせないでって
Before I grew to love you this much, please don't purposely mislead me with gentle words—
勝手でワガママだよね
how selfish and willful of me.
涙出るのは嘘でも強がるから
Tears fall because even lies make me put up a strong front,
気づかないふりしないで どうしても諦められないよ
don't pretend not to notice, I just can't give up.
終わった恋なのに こんなにもあなたのこと好きになってしまう前に
Even though this love is over, before I grew to love you this much,
せめてさよならの言葉告げて欲しかったなんて 勝手でワガママだよね
I wish you had at least said goodbye—how selfish and willful of me.
誰より想ってるのに あなたを世界で1番笑顔に変えられる人はきっと私じゃないから
Even though I care more than anyone, the person who can make you the happiest in the world surely isn't me, so
どうか幸せになって
please be happy.
どんなに願いがあっても 変わやしないこの現実がただただ目の前の光全て奪い去った
No matter how many wishes I have, this unchanging reality simply swept away all the light before me.
生まれ変わっても もう一度あなたに恋するかな そんなもの相違なんて 考えることすらも馬鹿みたい
Even if I'm reborn, would I fall in love with you again? Such thoughts—even thinking about them are foolish.
こんなもん？そんなもん？なんて考えることすらも馬鹿みたい
Is it like this? Is it like that? Even thinking about it is foolish.
馬鹿みたい
So foolish.
こんなにもあなたのこと好きになってしまう前に
Before I grew to love you this much,
わざとさ優しい言葉で勘違いさせないでって勝手でワガママだよね
please don't purposely mislead me with gentle words—how selfish and willful of me.
あなたの幸せそうな顔を見るだけで胸いっぱいになるあなたと私はきっとお似合いじゃないから
Just seeing your happy face fills my heart; you and I surely aren't a match, so
どうか幸せになって
please be happy.
顔を見るだけで胸いっぱいになるあなたと私はきっと
Just looking at your face fills my heart, you and I surely...
お似合いじゃないから どうか幸せになって
Aren't meant for each other, so please be happy.
涙出るのは嘘でも強がるから気づかないふりしないでどうしても諦められないよ終わった恋なのに
Tears fall because even if it's a lie I put on a strong front, don't pretend not to notice, I just can't give up even though our love is over.
自ずの言い訳しないで どうしても諦められないよ 終わった恋なのに
Don't make excuses to yourself, I just can't give up even though our love is over.
こんなにもあなたのこと
So much about you...
好きになってしまう前に せめてさ
Before I end up falling in love with you, at least...
さよならの言葉 つけて欲しかったなって
I wanted you to at least say goodbye...
勝手でわがままなんだよね
How selfish and headstrong of me.
こんな日も あなたのこと
Even on days like this, about you...
好きになってしまう前に せめてさ
Before I end up falling in love with you, at least...
さよならの言葉 つけて欲しかったなって
I wanted you to at least say goodbye...
勝手でわがままなんだよね
How selfish and headstrong of me.
誰より想っているのに あなたを世界で
Even though I care for you more than anyone else in the world...
一番笑顔に変えられるのはきっと 私じゃないから
The one who can bring out your biggest smile surely isn't me.
ぬくもりに寄せて
Drawing close to your warmth...
幸せになって
Be happy.
わ、だいぶみんな来てくれてありがとう！
Ah, thank you everyone for coming!
誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
ありがとう！おめでとう！
Thank you! Congratulations!
じゃあ最初は誰から自己紹介する？
So first, who's going to introduce themselves?
じゃあ俺から行こかな。ホロスターズ1期生の律可です。よろしくお願いします！
Guess I'll go first. I'm Rikka from Holostars 1st gen. Nice to meet you!
はい、ホロスターズの荒咬オウガです。よろしくお願いします！
Yes, I'm Aragami Oga from Holostars. Nice to meet you!
いやー、いおひといっしょに歌ってくれてありがとう。ほんとにありがとう！
Man, thank you so much for singing with me, Iofi. Really, thank you!
いやこちらこそ呼んでくれてありがとう。嬉しかった！
No, thank you for inviting me. I'm so glad!
で、なんかリッカパパとは私ガデビューの頃から結構お世話になってて
And, you know, Rikka-papa and I go way back since my debut...
日常茶飯事のことか、きてもらったりしたもんね。
Like everyday occurrences, you'd come over and stuff, right?
そうそう、なので今回歌いたいなと思ってて。呼んでくれてありがとう！
Yeah, exactly. So I wanted to sing together this time. Thanks for inviting me!
ではでは、オウガくんは？オウガくんは？
Now then, what about Oga-kun? What about Oga-kun?
後輩だもんな。後輩だもんな。そうだよな！
You're the junior here, right? That's right!
なんかスタジオであったときにさ、仕事でたまたまあのきらくに...
Like, when we met at the studio for work, totally casually...
じゃあ次の来年の誕生日にさ、あの歌ってくれる？って言ってくれて、まさか本当に呼んでくれると思わなくて、めちゃめちゃ嬉しかったの！
You told me, "Will you sing at my birthday next year?" I never thought you'd actually invite me, I was so happy!
いや違う違う違う！嬉しすぎてびっくりしちゃったよ、僕。ありがとうね！
No, wait! I was so happy and surprised myself. Thank you!
で、僕たち揃うのがあの、2年ぶりなんだよね？2年前？
And for the three of us to get together like this, it's been two years, right? Two years ago?
そう！ホロスターズサイドの簡単ライブで、あのこの3人とこぼちゃんで4人で歌わせていただいたんですけど、一緒に歌うのは実、それぶり？
Right! At the Holostars side's simple live, we sang as four with Kobachan, but singing together is actually since then?
ライブぶり？2年前？そう！もう2年経ったんだなーって感じ。
Since that live? Two years ago? Yeah! Feels like it's already been two years.
早いなー！早い！早いですよね。一緒に歌えてめちゃめちゃ楽しかったです！
Time flies! Fast! It really does. It was so much fun singing together!
いや何かさ、三人バンドみたいなの。ギター1人、ギター1人、なんかみたことある感じの画角で。
Like a three-person band setup. One guitar, another guitar, it's a familiar-looking framing.
じゃあ来年だったらもうバンドやります、そしたら。バンドね！じゃあ俺ドラムやろうかな。
Well, if it's next year, we'll do a band then. A band, huh? Then I'll play drums.
じゃあそしたら、なんかいい感じな...じゃあ俺トライアングルやるわ。
Then, something nice... I'll play the triangle.
あれ？なんで？なんでトライアングルやる？
Huh? Why? Why the triangle?
マラカス？
Maracas?
リズム感いらないじゃん！リズム叩いとけばいいじゃん！
You don't need rhythm sense for that! Just beat the rhythm!
ギターとかいないんだ！で、トライアングルとか思わなかった、こうキョロキョロしてさ。気持ちにカンバリにしようかな。
There's no guitar or anything! I didn't expect a triangle, looking around like that. Let's make it comfortable.
カンバリね！カンバリで。みんなうるさいやつじゃん！
Comfortable, huh! Comfortable with that. You guys are noisy!
音がしゃんしゃんしゃん！心地いいしゃんしゃんしゃん！
The sound goes shang shang shang! Pleasing shang shang shang!
今回結構しっとりだったから、確かにね。誰か分からないけど、やっぱりハモリ難しかったね、やっぱね。3人だからさ。
It was pretty mellow this time, that's true. I don't know who, but harmonies were hard, being three people.
そう、なんか元々さ、男子と女子がさ、なんかあの2人で歌う曲見つけるのちょっと結構難しくて。
Yeah, originally, for guys and girls finding a song to sing together, it's quite difficult.
確かにね！キーがね。うん、キーが、でも女子の曲だったらキー下げなきゃいけないし。
True! The keys. Yeah, the keys, but if it's a girl's song, we have to lower the key.
出せれたら、こっちが...こっちが低すぎるから、だからどうしようって。
If we sing it, our side is... too low, so we were like, what should we do?
でもめちゃめちゃ素敵な曲！ね、元気も出たしよかった！
But it's such a wonderful song! Yeah, it gave us energy, I'm glad!
うん、なんかゲストはあの、最初にはあ、やっぱり絶対にりょくんとリカパイセンをちょっと紹介、あの招待したんだけど、その時期に曲まだ決まってなくて。あ、そうなの！
Yeah, for the guests, at first I definitely wanted to invite Ryo-kun and Rikka-senpai, but at that time the song wasn't decided yet. Ah, is that so!
後から決まった。後から。そう、後から。
It was decided later. Later. Yeah, later.
いいのを見つけたね！ありがとう！本当に良かったよ。声も合ってたしこの3人の。うん、めちゃめちゃ良かった。
You found a great one! Thank you! It really was great. Our voices matched so well, the three of us. Yeah, it was super good.
いや、本当に良かった！そう、ゲストから、です、ゲストが決まってその曲、って感じね。
Yeah, really good! So, from the guests, the guests are decided, and then that song, like that.
いやでもまたやりたい気もね！え、やりたい。
But I'd love to do it again! Ah, I want to do it.
次もっ？
Next time too?
次はバンド？
A band next time?
バンドやれるか？やれるか！
Can we do a band? We can!
バンド、じゃあマラカス。
A band? Then maracas.
練習時間めっちゃかかりそうだけど、確かに。
Practice would take forever, that's true.
ドラムやったことないからな。
Since we've never played drums.
いや、仕方ない。
Well, can't be helped.
やるなら練習しますよ。
If we do it, we'll practice.
じゃあ来年やりますバンド。楽しみ！
Then next year we'll do a band. Can't wait!
もう本当にやりそうだから怖いな(笑)
It's scary because you'd actually do it! (Haha)
ということで来年楽しみにしてて、
With that said, look forward to next year!
みんな本気にするよ！みんな本気にしちゃうよ！
Everyone's gonna take it seriously!
こええ、こええ。(笑)
So scary, so scary. (Haha)
じゃあ来年と楽しみということで！
So we're looking forward to next year!
本当に皆さん見てくれてありがとう！これからもね、まだまだあるので…
Thank you everyone so much for watching! There's still more coming up...
楽しんでください！
Please enjoy!
はい、楽しんで、楽しんで、見てくれてありがとう！楽しんでねー！
Yes, enjoy, enjoy, thank you for watching! Have fun!
ぼくらのレッドイットビー
[Title: Our Let It Be]
生まれ変われるのなら
If I could be reborn,
目印に
as a landmark,
なるから巻いてとこう
I'll tie it up so you can find me.
小指と小指の長い糸 ほどけない様に 結んどこう
Like an unbreakable string between our pinkies, let's tie it tight.
夏祭り りんご飴
Summer festivals, candy apples,
雨降り空に 虹が架かる頃なの
right around when a rainbow bridges the rainy sky.
壊れた感情が いつか君を消していく
A broken heart will someday make you fade away...
A broken heart will someday make you fade away,
見えなくなると 失われる灯火
losing the light that vanishes from sight.
でも 結んだ長い糸 ほどけ落ちていないから
But because the tied string hasn't come undone,
また ぼくたちは 出会う時が来る きっと
surely, the time will come for us to meet again.
ぼくら おとなになったら せいぎのヒーローになるんだ
When we grow up, we'll become heroes of justice,
地球の平和を守るのさ 探検しようぜ おばけ屋敷
protecting the earth's peace. Let's explore a haunted house!
でも本当は こわくって 泣き虫 一緒に居たいだけ
But honestly, I'm terrified, a crybaby just wanting to stay by your side.
明日も晴れて空を 青く照らせば ぼくらは ここに ひみつきちを作ろう
If tomorrow's sky is sunny and shines blue, let's build a secret base right here.
そして探検しよう
And let's explore!
雨ならゲームをしよう
If it rains, we'll play games.
そんな時間が ずっと続くはずだったんだ
Such time was supposed to last forever...
そう 悪者は 僕だった 逃げたのは 僕だ
Yes, I was the bad guy, I was the one who ran away.
嘘じゃない 本当の嘘つきだ
It's no lie, I'm a true liar.
花束に 包まれて 目を瞑る君は
Enveloped in a bouquet, closing your eyes,
安らかに 清らかに 眠っていたんだ
you were sleeping peacefully and purely.
悪者ののは 僕だった 逃げたのは 僕だ
The bad guy was us, the one who ran away was us.
嘘じゃない 本当の嘘つきだ
It's no lie, I'm a true liar.
あなたばかり 包まれて
Wrapped only in you...
目を瞑る君は 安らかに 清らかに 眠っていたんだ
You, closing your eyes, were sleeping peacefully and purely.
見乱れて 痛んだ
Distraught and in pain.
壊れた感情が いつか君を消していく
A broken heart will someday make you fade away...
失う前に 消えてしまう前に
Before we lose it, before it disappears...
ただ 結んだ長い糸 ほどけ落ちていなかった
The tied string hadn't come undone after all.
Lama ku memendam rasa di dada
For a long time I kept my feelings in my chest
Mengagumi indahmu, wahai jelita
Admiring your beauty, oh beautiful one
Tak dapat lagi ku ucap kata
I can no longer speak a word
Bisuku diam terpesona
I am stunned and fascinated
Dan andai suatu hari kau jadi milikku
And if one day you become mine
Tak akan kulepas dirimu, oh kasih
I will never let you go, oh dear
Dan bila waktu mengizinkan ku untuk menunggu dirimu
And if time allows me to wait for you
Kurasa ku tlah jatuh cinta
I feel like I've fallen in love
Pada pandangan yang pertama
At first sight
Sulit bagiku untuk bisa
It's hard for me to
Berhenti mengagumi dirinya
Stop admiring her
Seiring dengan berjalannya waktu
As time goes by
Akhirnya kita berdua bertemu
Finally we both met
Oh diriku tersipu malu
Oh, I blushed in embarrassment
Melihat sikapmu yang lucu
Seeing your funny attitude
Dan andai suatu hari kau jadi milikku
And if one day you become mine
Tak akan kulepas dirimu, oh kasih
I will never let you go, oh dear
Dan bila waktu mengizinkan ku untuk menunggu dirimu
And if time allows me to wait for you
Kurasa ku tlah jatuh cinta
I feel like I've fallen in love
Pada pandangan yang pertama
At first sight
Sulit bagiku untuk bisa
It's hard for me to
Berhenti mengagumi dirinya
Stop admiring her
Oh tuhan tolonglah diriku
Oh God, help me
Tuk membuat dia menjadi milikku
To make her mine
Sayangku, kasihku, oh cintaku
My love, my dear, oh my love
She's all that I need
Dan bila kita bersama
And if we are together
Kan kujaga dirimu untuk selamanya
I will take care of you forever
Oh terima cintaku
Please accept my love
Summertime, ain't a summertime, if I don't have you as mine, but you're always on my mind, yeah
In the magazine you showed up, baby girl your beauty makes my mind blow up
Your personality it's calm and friendly, the kinda girl that I would love to be with me
Once I start, no I won't fall back, here's my cell phone number, so please call back, come on!
Kurasa ku tlah jatuh cinta
I feel like I've fallen in love
Pada pandangan yang pertama
At first sight
Sulit bagiku untuk bisa
It's hard for me to
Berhenti mengagumi dirinya
Stop admiring her
Oh tuhan tolonglah diriku
Oh God, help me
Tuk membuat dia menjadi milikku
To make her mine
Sayangku, kasihku, oh cintaku
My love, my dear, oh my love
She's all that I need
Pesawat Kertas 365 Hari
365-Day Paper Airplane
Ku tatap langit di pagi hari
I looked up at the morning sky
Ku awali hari dengan doa
And started the day with a prayer
Semoga satu hari ini bisa
Hoping today could be
Dipenuhi oleh senyum
Filled with smiles
Walaupun terkadang hujan turun
It rains every now and then,
Dan air mata juga mengalir
And my eyes flood with tears
Besok pun tetap semangat
Di dalam mimpiku selalu
I've always had this dream
Terlihat ada diriku sendiri
One where I'm all alone
Yang dengan bebasnya melakukan semua
And I'm free to do all those things
Hal yang ingin aku lakukan
Whatever I'd like to do
Hidup bagaikan pesawat kertas
Life is a paper airplane
Terbang dan pergi membawa impian
Flying away with our dreams
Sekuat tenaga dengan hembusan angin
Propelled strongly by the wind
Terus melaju terbang
Continuing to soar forward
Jangan bandingkan jarak terbangnya
Don't compare how far it flew
Dan apa yang dilalui
But what it went through
Karena itulah satu hal yang penting
Because that is what truly matters
S'lalu sesuai kata hati
Always following your heart
Sanbyaku rokujugo nichi
365 days of the year
Di saat terlihat bintang-bintang
When stars fill the sky
Atau malam yang gelap gulita
Or during dark, gloomy nights
Pada saat semangatmu hilang carilah
When you lose your spirit, look for someone
Orang lain dan bicara
To talk to and share your thoughts
Manusia tidaklah pernah
People are never truly
Ditinggal sendirian saja
Left all alone by themselves
Terkadang kita tak menyadari
Sometimes we just don't realize
Hal baik di sekitar kita
The kindness right beside us
Hidup bagaikan pesawat kertas
Life is a paper airplane
Terbang dan membawa cinta kita semua
Flying and carrying all our love
Sayap yang terbentang dengan percaya diri
Spreading its wings with confidence
Dilihat semua orang
For everyone to see
Walau tak tahu cara melipatnya
Even if we don't know how to fold it
Suatu saat pasti akan berhasil lalu terbang
It will surely succeed and fly one day
Kekuatan harapan yang menerbangkannya
Propelled by the power of hope
Ya, mari nikmatilah
Oh, let's just enjoy it
Sanbyaku rokujugo nichi
365 days of the year
Hidup bagaikan pesawat kertas
Life is a paper airplane
Terbang dan pergi membawa impian
Flying away with our dreams
Sekuat tenaga dengan hembusan angin
Propelled strongly by the wind
Terus melaju terbang
Continuing to soar forward
Jangan bandingkan jarak terbangnya
Don't compare how far it flew
Dan apa yang dilalui
But what it went through
Karena itulah satu hal yang penting
Because that is what truly matters
S'lalu sesuai kata hati
Always following your heart
Sanbyaku rokujugo nichi
365 days of the year
Ayo terbanglah,
Go on, fly!
coba terbanglah
Let's fly!
Ku tatap langit di pagi hari
I looked up at the morning sky
Ku awali hari dengan doa
and quietly made a wish
Semoga satu hari ini bisa
that I’d be able to smile
Dipenuhi oleh senyum
all day today
Walaupun terkadang hujan turun
it rains every now and then,
Dan air mata juga mengalir
and my eyes flood with tears
Di hari yang tak berjalan dengan mulus
but if your day’s not going how you hoped
Besok pun tetap semangat
let’s just do the best we can tomorrow instead
Hah! Akhirnya ya, Pi.
Ha! Finally, Pi.
Akhirnya ya, collab kecil-kecilan kita
Finally, our small-scale collab
enggak kecil, udah jadi besar, Guys!
isn't small anymore, it's huge, guys!
Oh my god, lu lihat gue dong.
Oh my god, look at me.
Hai! Hai!
Hi! Hi!
Akhirnya ya, Pi, collab kecil-kecilan kita
Finally, Pi, our small collab
enggak kecil, udah jadi besar, Guys! Yay!
is no longer small. It's huge, guys! Yay!
Finally!
Terima kasih.
Thank you.
Terima kasih sudah mengundang saya, Senpai.
Thank you for inviting me, Senpai.
Oi, Senpai! Iya, Senpai!
Hey, Senpai! Yeah, Senpai!
Berapa sudah? Ulang tahun yang ke berapa, Senpai?
How many is it? What number birthday is it?
Enam!
Six!
Tapi kok belum lulus-lulus juga?
But why haven't you graduated yet?
Eh, daripada gitu, mending dikosokin aja dulu.
Instead of that, you'd better clear it up first.
We are on fire!
Semangat membara, yang menghangatkan hari-harimu!
Burning passion that warms your days!
Halo, aku Pamaraleon dari JKT48 Virtual Grand Prix
Hello, I'm Pamaraleon from the JKT48 Virtual Grand Prix
yang pertama. Halo semuanya!
first. Hello everyone!
Halo! Oh my god, yes!
Hello! Oh my god, yes!
By the way, aku, aku nyadar sesuatu. Tahu enggak?
By the way, I, I noticed something. You know what?
Apa?
What?
Sorry, so basically buat kalian yang bilang aku lebih pendek, now you guys see.
Sorry, so basically for those of you who said I'm shorter, now you guys see.
Alah, dikit doang.
Come on, just a little.
Dikit doang means everything to me, you know? Means everything.
"Just a little" means everything to me, you know? Means everything.
Oh, ya sudah doang, tinggiku berapa?
Oh, whatever, how tall am I?
Ah, oke, duduk aja yuk.
Ah, okay, let's just sit down.
Well, for your information, oh, enggak banyak kok, paling 18 cm.
Well, for your information, oh, it's not that much, maybe 18 cm.
Tapi, tapi ya jika kaki aku enggak nyampe.
But, but yeah, if my feet don't reach.
See? Oh my god, guys. Dia, dia tuh emang, look at that,
See? Oh my god, guys. She, she really, look at that,
ngambang, cuy! Bro, ngambang for no reason!
she's floating, man! Bro, floating for no reason!
Asyik, enggak kelar-kelar.
Awesome, never ends.
Ya, pi, ada sih, beda. Ini, tonton sini!
Yeah, Pi, there is a difference. Here, watch this!
Ini, lihat! Tuh, enggak.
Here, look! See, no.
Jadi ya, untuk lagu ini ya, koreografinya free style. Aku dikasih tahu sama Pia, Pia yang kasih tahu.
So yeah, for this song, the choreography is freestyle. Pia told me, Pia taught me.
Aku dikasih tahu sama Pia, Pia yang kasih tahu, seru.
Pia taught me, Pia taught me, it's fun.
Ayo terbanglah, coba terbanglah
Go on, fly! Let’s fly!
Ih, lucu banget kan? Asyik. Iya, gitu.
Ah, so cute, right? Fun. Yeah, like that.
Guys, tolong don't judge me.
Guys, please don't judge me.
Don't judge me. We're learning, oke? We're learning.
Don't judge me. We're learning, okay? We're learning.
Iya, lah, ni. Jadi kalau ada apa-apa, ya, ke Pia. Enggak gitu, ya?
Yeah, right. So if anything happens, blame Pia. Not like that, right?
Anyway, what is this?
Karena kamu mau ke sini, aku pakaiin peri nih.
Because you wanted to come here, I put a fairy on it.
Really? Is this like for me?
Iya. Coba-coba. Dilihatin, dilihatin, Ma. We are on fire!
Yeah. Try it. Look at it, look at it, Ma. We are on fire!
Aku so anget, guys. Coba. Bau kue.
I'm so warm, guys. Try it. Smells like cake.
Sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry.
Nih, kalau kalian penasaran, nih bau nya Pia kayak gini, Guys.
Here, if you guys are curious, Pia's smell is like this, guys.
Iya, bau arang. Bau abu. Bau arang tuh bau kue, cuy.
Yeah, smells like charcoal. Smells like ash. Charcoal smells like cake, man.
Eh, lucu, cuy. Tapi, oh my god, konek.
Hey, cute, man. But, oh my god, connected.
Tapi, aku suka banget, Kak.
But, I really like it, Kak.
Enggak mau pulang, boleh enggak? Bau pulang?
Don't want to go home, is that okay? Smell going home?
Itu, iya. Terima kasih ya, manajernya Pia sudah apa, meminjamkan saya. Terima kasih.
That, yeah. Thank you, Pia's manager, for, what, lending me. Thank you.
Enchan, arigatou!
Iya, Kak. Enchan.
Yes, Kak. Enchan.
Iya, my god, I cannot really...
Yeah, my god, I cannot really...
Oh, Siku. Akhirnya aku bisa manggil kamu tuh, Guys.
Oh, Siku. Finally I can call you that, guys.
Aku tuh, Guys, waktu pertama kali bilang, "Aku mau invite kamu," aku kayak, "Hah? Nani?"
I was like, Guys, the first time I said, "I want to invite you," I was like, "Huh? Nani?"
Aku kayak, manajerku kayak, "Kalau bisa aku pegang," kayak, "Wah!" Aku diundang sama Siku, gitu.
I was like, my manager was like, "If I can hold it," like, "Wow!" I was invited by Siku, like that.
Iya, begitu. Tapi ya, tapi ya setting harus pulang, Bro.
Yeah, like that. But yeah, but the setting is we have to go home, Bro.
Oh, iya, benar. Oh, ya thank you for coming.
Oh, yeah, right. Oh, yeah, thank you for coming.
Yeah, it's okay, thank you. You know, enjoy the rest of the show.
I will watch from there.
Oke, siap. Cepat-cepat.
Okay, got it. Hurry up.
Bye-bye, arigatou. Thank you!
Yuhuu, ya! Oh, bisa. Kita sudah di penghujung acara nih, Guys. Yeay!
Yuhuu, yeah! Oh, we can. We're already at the end of the show, guys. Yay!
Tapi sebelum kita ke akhir acara, aku akan berterima kasih dulu. Terima kasih sudah datang. Mwah!
But before we get to the end of the show, I will say thank you first. Thank you for coming. Mwah!
Terus sama arigatou dekapase, arigatou, Ryo-kun, arigatou, Pia juga terima kasih dan di dan di Sweden mu.
And also arigatou dekapase, arigatou, Ryo-kun, arigatou, Pia also thank you and in your Sweden.
Terima kasih semuanya!
Thank you, everyone!
Iya, akhirnya ya, Iofi punya birthday celebration 2025 sudah di ujung acara.
Yes, finally, Iofi's 2025 birthday celebration is coming to an end.
Tapi jangan skip ads dulu sebelum berakhir, aku punya sesuatu untuk kalian.
But don't skip the ads yet before it ends, I have something for you.
Teta-o! Birthday merch set. Tada! Babam!
Tada! Birthday merch set. Tada! Babam!
Hai, iofi birthday 2025 kita punya tiga merch dan sesuatu yang spesial dan voice.
Hi! For Iofi's 2025 birthday, we have three merch items, something special, and a voice pack.
Mari kita lihat ya, tonton!
Let's check it out, watch!
Hai! ioDreaming blanket, aku akan keep kamu warm 24/7.
Hi! ioDreaming blanket, I'll keep you warm 24/7.
Iofi-ka atatakaku susundeageru yo, koya-tte, kyu-tto ne, attakai kara ne.
Iofi will keep you warm, hugging you tight because it's warm.
Aduh dingin, terus ditemani hangat ini, aku akan menemani malam-malammu yang dingin.
It's cold, but accompanied by this warmth, I'll accompany your cold nights.
Toshi-ko-toshi mo irasuto wa mitsuki-mama, arigatou! Minasan mo mama arigatou!
This year's illustration is once again by Mitsuki-mama, thank you! Thank you to everyone's mama too!
Lucu sekali, fua-fua, kawaii.
It's so cute, fluffy, adorable.
Etappi, kalau sudah ada blanket berarti kurang apa sih? Ah, next time!
Next, if there's a blanket, what's missing? Ah, next one!
We have this one! Sweet Dreams Pillow Cover. Sya... ah...
We have this one! Sweet Dreams Pillow Cover. Yeah... ah...
Didin-in mislain. Tapi kayaknya kepala kalian bisa pas buat di...
It's so dreamy. But I think your heads will fit right in...
This guy, it's so fua-fua, it's so comfy, you can place your head right in... yeah!
It's so fluffy, so comfy, you can place your head right in... yeah!
Anu, kore, ini isinya kayak gini. Ah, de-mo de-mo de-mo, Iofi-ni muchu sugi de chotto jikan wasurechau.
Um, this is what's inside. But, but, but, I get so absorbed in Iofi that I lose track of time.
Ah, yabai, doushiyou tte toki wa kotsura desu! Dreaming Palette Acrylic Clock.
Ah, oh no, what should I do? That's when this comes in! Dreaming Palette Acrylic Clock.
So you won't really forget about time while thinking about me.
Kayai desu. Ah, de-mo de-mo de-mo, tsugi tsugi tsugi tsugi, tsugi wa nan nan da? Ah, kotsura desu!
How cute. But, but, but, next, next, what's next? Ah, here it is!
Situational Voice Pack "Dream Rendezvous" (Japanese & Indonesian & English) So you will be meeting me in a dream, so you may de mo aeru you ni, kono voice wo kiite ne. Hai! De mo kiite ne.
So you will be meeting me in a dream, so that you can meet me anytime, please listen to this voice. Yes!
De de de, kotoshi ga atarashii no, watashi no detekuru no yo. There's gonna be something new this year
And this year, something new of mine is coming out! There's gonna be something new this year!
and this is set! Bam!
And this is it! Bam!
If you buy the full version, there's gonna be a hololive card game! Yeah! This is a bonus hololive card.
Ini sebagai bonus pemberian full set premium. Premium merch ini akan tambahan bonus kartu yang bisa kalian pakai di game-nya official hololive, guys!
This is a bonus for purchasing the premium full set. This premium merch adds a bonus card you can use in the official Hololive game, guys!
You can actually use it on a, on a game. Yeah! Kalau ini sa, taikai toka de tsukattara sa, meccha jiman dekimasu yo, koya-tte.
You can actually use it in the game. Yeah! If you use this in tournaments, you can show it off so much like this.
Core ga Iofi no gentei no tanjoubi gukku kara deta n ya. Hoi!
This came right from Iofi's limited birthday goods. Hoi!
De mo maa omamori toshite mo ne, koko ni oite te mo daijoubu desu yo, Iofi ga koko ni iru kara.
But well, as a talisman, it's okay to put it here too, because Iofi is right here.
Iya, jadi ini borum bisa dipakai di card ya, di game-nya oshi horomen card to, tapi kartu hari ini yang ini sayang sekali baru ada bahasa Jepang-nya.
Yeah, so this volume can be used in cards, in the Hololive Oshi Card Game, but unfortunately, today's card only has Japanese for now.
Untuk di kartu dan cara bermain bisa dicek di homepage. Begitu, guys, terima kasih!
You can check the homepage for the card details and how to play. That's it, guys, thank you!
Dan kita sudah sampai di pengunjung-ujung-ujung-ujung acara.
And we have reached the very, very, very end of the event.
Hmm, jadi karena tahun lalu kita sudah dengar, "Here I am" yang biasa. Nah, tahun ini aku punya yang spesial untuk kalian.
Hmm, because last year we heard the usual "Here I am", well, this year I have something special for you.
Here I am full Bahasa Indonesia. Ah, here I am Indonesian version.
Here I am in full Indonesian. Ah, here I am Indonesian version.
Tapi itu hanya untuk membership. Yang bikin gentei de "Here I am" Indonesia version, nanti di-uta-i-masu. Hai!
But that's only for membership. It's exclusive, the Indonesian version of "Here I am", I'll sing it later. Yes!
Jadi habis ini akan, apa ya? Aku akan ketemu kalian di membership, ok?
So after this, what's next? I'll meet you guys in membership, okay?
De wa, honto no honto no honto no saigo no kyoku ni narimasu. Hai, this will be my last song for tonight.
Well then, this will truly, truly, truly be the very last song. Yes, this will be my last song for tonight.
I hope you're ready. This last song will be Kokoro no Sakamichi, shua de...
I hope you're ready. This last song will be "Kokoro no Sakamichi", sure...
何度も苦しい思いをした
I've been through pain more times than I can say
何度も悲しい思いもした
I've felt the sorrow that wouldn't go away
今日までたくさん歩いてきた
Step by step, I've made it here today
心の坂道を
Up the hill where my feelings lay
歩き慣れた変える道、ふと躓いた
I tripped and fell on the road I always take
不意打ちみたいで
Caught off guard, like a sudden break
まるで裏切られた気分
It hit me like a stab in the back
踏んだ
破けたジーンズと 心の隙間 埋まり
In turn-up jeans and a heart with a crack
冷たい風が抜け 恋い焦がれ疾走て
The cold wind gently passes through
恋い仕草と疾走て 一歩を踏み出すと
I kick a pebble as I move on too
一歩を踏み出すと 君が行ってくれた
The moment I took a single step ahead
君が行ってくれた
I found you standing there instead
何度も苦しい思いをした
I've been through pain more times than I can say
何度も悲しい思いをした
I've felt the sorrow that wouldn't go away
今日までたくさん歩いてきた
Step by step, I've made it here today
心の坂道は 坂道は
Up the hill where my feelings lay
君がいたから強くなれた
Because you were there for me
傷だらけであって 坂道も歩けた
I found the strength to be
君がいるから 歩いて行けるさ
Even with scars, I climbed that hill with ease
涙の跡残さないで
Leaving no tears for the world to see
あの日 君は言っていた
That day, you said to me
本当の強さは 泣いてもまた笑えることだよ
True strength is being able to cry, then smile again, you know?
何度も苦しい思いをした
I've been through pain more times than I can say
何度も悲しい思いをした
I've felt the sorrow that wouldn't go away
今日までたくさん歩いてきた
Step by step, I've made it here today
心の坂道は 心の坂道は
Up the hill where my feelings lay
君がいたから強くなれた
Because you were there for me
傷だらけであって 坂道も歩けた
I found the strength to be
君がいるから歩いて行けるさ
Even with scars, I climbed that hill with ease
涙の跡残さないで
Because you're here with me
君がいたから 君がいたから
I know I'll keep walking free
君がいるから 君がいるから
Leaving no tears for the world to see
イエイイエー
Because you're here with me